hey everybody welcome to this b1 english
listening practice video
you can use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension as i speak
before we start remember to sign up for
our one dollar listening practice
seminars at polyglossa.com
and download the free listening time
podcast so you can practice your
listening skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about phones
i was talking about this topic the other
day and i got to thinking about how
important
phones are in our everyday lives so
let's talk a little bit about this
let's go briefly through the history of
phones even though some basic versions
of the telephone had been invented
earlier
alexander graham bell is usually
credited with the invention since he won
the first
u.s patent for it a patent is a
government license given to someone who
comes up with an idea for an invention
it excludes other people from making or
selling this invention for a certain
number of
years so alexander graham bell received
a patent for the telephone in 1876.
prior to that people couldn't talk over
long distances
they could only send messages through
telegraph or some other means
you can imagine how revolutionary this
invention was when suddenly people could
talk and have their voice heard in a
different location
it must have seemed like really advanced
technology at the time
but obviously telephones didn't just
become common household items overnight
it would be decades before this device
became commonplace and at the turn of
the century there were still fewer than
a million phones in use
one big milestone in the development of
phones was the first
transcontinental phone call which was
made from new york to san francisco in
1915.
nowadays this might not seem like a huge
feat but this type of long distance
communication was completely unheard of
at that time
the telephone was changing the way
people thought about communication
over the next few decades many more
millions of households installed
landlines
and the telephone became the king of
communication
then fast forward to 1973 in the world
saw the introduction of the first cell
phone made by motorola
but if you're thinking that this cell
phone bore any resemblance to today's
phones
think again the first mobile phone was a
monster
it definitely couldn't fit in anyone's
pocket later on
in 1989 the first flip phone appeared on
the market
a flip phone is a phone that you open
like this the type of phone that i had
growing up
in 1992 the first text message was sent
between phones
obviously today text messages are an
essential function of all cell phones
and people communicate more through
messages than they do through calls
come to think of it it seems like people
try to avoid calling
and instead send text messages whenever
possible
another cell phone feature that we take
for granted nowadays is the camera
the first camera phone came out in japan
in 1999
and then later on in the rest of the
world and then finally in 2007
the first iphone came out stunning the
world with its revolutionary design
and touch screen display even though
there were already smartphones in
existence at that time
the iphone really brought smartphones
onto the scene
after that other companies followed suit
and started releasing smartphone after
smartphone
nowadays it seems like practically
everyone who can afford it has a
smartphone
this device has become a necessity in
many people's lives and most people
spend many hours every week using it
actually a lot of people don't even use
their computer that much anymore because
they can do everything from their phone
if you had told people just a few
decades ago about the cell phones of
today
they probably wouldn't have believed you
who knows what type of innovation we
might see with phones in the future
i guess we'll have to wait and see okay
now i'm going to ask you three questions
about today's video
write your answers in a comment down
below number one
in what year was the first
transcontinental phone call made
number two which company made the
world's first cell phone
and number three what important cell
phone feature was first added in 1992
all right before we go remember to sign
up for our 1 listening practice seminars
and download the free listening time
podcast so you can practice your
listening skills
and of course subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram i'll see you
next time